Finding Aid for Carmen A. Roberts Papers 1972-1981
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Carmen A. Roberts Papers 1972-1981
Roberts, Carmen A.
0.5 linear ft. and 1 volume
Member of the Detroit school board and a leader of the anti-busing movement in Detroit. Correspondence, speeches, clippings, legal brief, organizational miscellanea, and collected pro- and anti-busing materials; also photographs and motion picture film.
8721 AA Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Carmen A. Roberts (donor no. 7356 ) and came to the library in 1986.
The collection is open for research.
Carmen A. Roberts was a member of the Detroit school board and a leader of the anti-busing movement in Detroit in the mid-1970s.
The Roberts papers document her activities in the anti-busing movement in the Detroit area in the mid-1970s. The papers include correspondence, speeches, clippings, legal brief, organizational miscellanea, and collected pro- and anti-busing materials. There are also photographs of anti-busing demonstrations and a motion picture film of 1976 anti-busing rally.
Subjects:
Busing for school integration--Michigan--Detroit.; Detroit (Mich.). Board of Education.; Education--Michigan--Detroit.; Segregation in education--Michigan--Detroit.; Women in education--Michigan--Detroit; Women in politics--Michigan--Detroit.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Activists.; Busing (School integration); Demonstrations.; Detroit (Mich.); Political parades and rallies.; Roberts, Carmen A.; Women--Political life.
Genre/Form:
Motion pictures.; Photographs.
- Papers
  - Biographical field notes (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1976, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Speeches, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Clippings
    - 1972 (Box 1)
    - 1973 (Box 1)
    - 1974 (Box 1)
    - 1975 (Box 1)
    - January-May 1976 (Box 1)
    - June-December 1976 (Box 1)
    - 1977 (Box 1)
    - 1979-1981 (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook, January-April 1976, (largely clippings, but also some photographs and correspondence) (Volume 1)
  - Northeast Mothers Association (NEMA), Anti-busing Brief, April 17, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Mothers Alert Detroit, 1975-1975 (Box 1)
  - National Association for Neighborhood Schools, 1976-1981 (Box 1)
  - Anti-busing Material, ca. 1976 (Box 1)
  - Pro-busing Material, ca. 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Let's Make It Work Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
- Visual Materials
  - Photographs (Box 1)
  - Film of Anti-busing Rally, 1976, 8 mm (Box 1)